# **Elochukwu Aroh**

#### **Software Developer**

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Email: elochukwuaroh@gmail.com

Address: 555 Keenleyside Street R2K3P6, Winnipeg, Manitoba

Phone: +1 587-357-2325

Link: Personal Portfolio Website: https://elochukwuaroh.com -----

### **OBJECTIVE**

A detail-oriented Software Developer, with about 2 years of experience building and maintaining mobile and web applications. Eager to join your challenging work environment, utilizing my technical skills in creating responsive, user-friendly, and customer-oriented projects.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

Apr 2021 - Jan 2022

#### Sales Associate

I-Pull U-Pull Auto Parts, Canada

- Served as one of the frontline brand representatives welcoming and directing customers around store
  merchandise, operating the cash register, and maintaining floor appearance.
- Maintained the status of the company's highest grossing sales personnel with impeccable customer service and devotion to duty.

#### Asaba, Delta State, Nigeria

Apr 2017 - Apr 2021

#### **Data Analyst**

Delta State Contributory Health Commission

- · Performing initial analysis to assess the quality of data.
- · Removal of corrupted data.
- Preparation and presentation of organizational data charts and projections.
- · The verification of enrollee status for payment of claims of services rendered by Healthcare Providers.
- · Enrollee and Healthcare facility database management, ensure data accuracy and integrity.
- · The preparation of the monthly Facility enrollee list and accompanying documents.
- · Enrollee and Facility level crisis resolution.
- Selected as one of 3 Baseline Enumerators for the Warri North Local Government Area to research and document the state of primary Healthcare delivery in the region. This facilitated in making my stateowned health insurance scheme the highest ranked in the country.

## Warri, Delta state, Nigeria

## Hardware maintenance and installations personnel (Intern)

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

Hi-tech Distributors. Computers and Office supplies

- · Hardware maintenance and repairs
- · Installation of equipment purchased by costumers

## Warri, Delta State, Nigeria

Jul 2016 - Mar 2017

#### Sales Associate

J.G ALSP NIG. ENT

· Cover regional supplies and sales.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Benin City, Nigeria** Sep 2012 - Jun 2016 **BSc Computer Science** 

Benson Idahosa University

Winnipeg, Manitoba

2022 - Present

Warri, Delta State

2017 - 2017

**Diploma Software Development** 

Manitoba Institute of Trades and Technology

**Diploma Web Development** 

Cct

**LANGUAGES** 

SKILLS

English

Advanced

**Ibo (Nigerian language)** 

Very good

Javascript

C# ReactJS

HTML5/CSS Object Oriented programming

Project Management Pro-efficiency in Microsoft Word, Excel,

**Powerpoint** 

MVC

Team player Time Management

**PROJECTS** 

N.B All projects host on my personal website https://elochukwuaroh.com

**Elo-TV:** This was a page built with React.js using the 'moviedbapi' to display show information from the big movie streaming platforms.

**Expense-Chart:** An application built with React.js that allows a user to add daily expenses thereby creating a description and bar chart on a monthly basis.

Pig-Game: A beautiful user interface designed with vanilla Javascript of the popular pig game.

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Project Management Course, July 2016

Health Services Standard Quality Control training by PharnAccess Group, March 2019

Cyber-Security Ethics in Health Information Management by the National Health Insurance Scheme,

November 2019

Teamwork and Work Place Ethics by Streamline Group, April 2019

Workplace Hazardous Material Information System Certified (GHS 2015), December 2021

**REFERENCES** 



Available on request